Pawan Gurung

Java Developer

gurungpawan7710@gmail.com

9845945761

Lalitpur, Nepal

Java Developer with 3+ years of experience developing enterprise software for banks and government. Participated in all aspects of the software development lifecycle. Seeking a challenging and growth-oriented Java developer position in a dynamic organization where I can apply my skills and experience to make a positive impact.

SKILLS

- Java, MVC, Spring Boot Framework
- SQL and database design
- Design patterns, Data Structure
- gRPC, Protobuff, MQTT, Docker, Redis
- Html5, CSS, Bootstrap, Thymeleaf
- · RESTful web services
- Agile software development
- Git version control

EDUCATION

Bsc CSIT (Bachelor)

Birendra Multiple Campus, TU Chitwan, Nepal (2015 - 2019)

REFERENCE

Kiran Subedi

Senior Software Engineer 9866019654

EXPERIENCE

Java Backend Developer

Treeleaf.ai, Lalitpur

March, 2021 - Now

- Managed records of around 1 million individuals for a traffic police application
 using Java, Redis, and MySQL, and expanded its use from Kathmandu Valley to
 all 7 states of Nepal by redesigning the architecture, developing REST APIs, and
 altering the database.
- Developed a REST API and designed a database from scratch using the docx4j library for a banking application that automated legal document generation, resulting in 80% time savings.
- Developed and implemented key features for an in-house project on the backend and database side, including adding reply functionality to the messaging section using MQTT and REST, and contributing to the workflow section
- Mentored and provided technical guidance to junior team members and participated in code reviews.

Java Developer

Pwnbot Systems, Chitwan

Aug, 2020 - Mar, 2021

- Integrated multiple third-party APIs like Google Workspace, WhatsApp, and Viber, to enhance application functionality and improve user experience.
- Optimized REST API by reducing payload size, leveraging database indexes, implementing caching mechanisms, and optimizing database queries.
- Consistently wrote clean, maintainable, and solid code, adhering to best practices and industry standards to ensure high-quality software development.

Trainee

Unelma Platforms, Chitwan

Oct, 2017 - Dec, 2018

- Acquired knowledge of key coding principles, including YAGNI, SOLID, and DRY approaches, to improve code quality and maintainability.
- Gained experience in front-end development.
- Received daily mentoring and collaborated with a team of senior developers, gaining exposure to software troubleshooting and testing to enhance my skills and knowledge.